here's something interesting the area of
a regular octagon equals the product of
its longest and shortest diagonal here's
a visual proof
we can split the Octagon like this
and get these triangles
let's rearrange these parts
[Music]
all the parts combine to form this
rectangle
so the area of the Octagon is same as
the area of this rectangle
and we know that the area of the
rectangle equals the product of its
length and breadth
now let's go back to the octagon
[Music]
the length of the rectangle will be same
as the longest diagonal and the breadth
of the rectangle will be same as the
shortest diagonal
so the area of the Octagon is same as
the product of its longest and shortest
diagonals
[Music]